Amuda Ifeoluwa Opeyemi

System Administrator

Address House 1, Efab Estate Life Camp, Nigeria,

900108

Phone 803-925-4192

E-mail info.htreasure@gmail.com

Driven Systems Administrator with 10 years of experience in software implementation and maintenance. Proven history of managing complex infrastructures and data center operations. Expert in solutions-oriented business application problem-solving and dedicated to providing best-in-class service. Skilled at troubleshooting, communication and collaboration.

Skills

Program installations	
	Excellent
System Updates / upgrades	Excellent
Server maintenance	Excellent
Hardware and software installation	Excellent
Virtualization	Fyra all and
Windows (Lines On another a Contains	Excellent
Windows / Linux Operating System	Excellent
Servers expertise / Storage virtualization	Excellent
Microsoft office	Excellent
Skilled in Apache / Samba proficiency	Very Good
Mass Storage Deployment	
	Very Good
Adaptability / Multitasking abilities	Very Good
Organization and Time management	Excellent

TCP/IP protocol	Very Good
Hardware troubleshooting	Excellent
Technical training	Excellent
Data management	Very Good

Work History

2021-04 - Current

Network Administrator

Bright 98.7 FM Abuja, Gwarinpa, FC

- Managed and maintained stability of network and wireless services for over 20 staff
- Performed day-to-day LAN and WAN administration, maintenance and support.
- Configured networks for smooth, reliable operation to meet business processes and objectives.
- Planned, coordinated and implemented network security measures.
- Identified and immediately resolved issues with network devices, including firewalls, router and streaming devices.
- Introduced Proxmox infrastructure and management tools to create and manage virtual server computing environment..
- Drafted training materials and organized training sessions for new employees.
- Maintained network hardware and software and monitored network to support network availability to end users.
- Installed, configured, and supported local area network (LAN), wide area network (WAN) and Internet system.
- Backed up company data to distributed storage centers to avoid massive data loss in event of network breach or failure.

2021-03 - Current

Data Center Manager

Briech Data, Maitama, FC

- Worked closely with management teams to plan, develop, coordinate and execute technical strategies aligned to client's vision, mission and purpose.
- Assessed existing systems including billing automation, accounting and real-time reporting and analytics capabilities, delivering updates for security purposes.
- Led team for software engineering services and supported key clients in development efforts, establishing standards, determining specifications and creating Service and Operational Level Agreements (SLA) and (OLA).
- Guided implementation of company-wide enterprise security strategy for network and hardware, disaster recovery, data protection and endpoint protection.

- Facilitated best user experience through continuous support, training classes, webinars, improvements and communication of system changes.
- Led and assisted technical upgrade projects for clients by working and coordinating with consultants and developers for integrations.
- Analyzed network security and current infrastructure to assess areas in need of improvement and develop solutions.
- Liaised effectively with others to promote on-going network design, reevaluation and optimization that scaled with company growth.
- Implemented and managed wireless devices, multi-site network infrastructure, business intelligence development and implementation.
- Interviewed, hired, trained and mentored 3 staff by coaching daily, leading performance reviews and offering constructive feedback.

2020-03 - Current

Tech Manager / Team Lead

TSTV Head Office, Idu Industrial District, FC

- Headed and successfully managed multi-department rollout of robust, flexible and secure electronic data interchange.
- Managed implementation of new technological improvements resulting in increased efficiency.
- Analyzed project-related information and made recommendations based on discoveries.
- Guided, coached and lead project teams, delegating tasks and evaluating performance and progression of project pace.
- Evaluated project risk on multiple dimension, including customer impact risk, reputation risk and regulatory risk.
- Increased employee productivity by 30% through training.
- Met with clients to gather and understand requirements and coordinated with system administrators and directors to plan and schedule project activities.
- Designed, implemented and monitored integration between applications while coordinating updates and developing test cases.
- Recruited and trained IT team members.

2017-01 - 2019-10

Network Administrator

Afe Babalola University, Ado Ekiti, Ado-Ekiti, EK

- Managed data backups and disaster recovery operations for 150-person company.
- Supervised 100 external computer consultants and vendors.
- Monitored data transfer security to detect and prevent intrusion attempts and respond to DDoS attacks.
- Provided network support services for devices such as hubs, bridges, routers and other hardware.
- Organized frameworks for transferring secure data from internal to external and public networks.
- Monitored network capacity and performance to diagnose and resolve complex network problems.

- Integrated fixed wireless connectivity into facilities lacking access to terrestrial high-speed networks.
- Provided complete end-to-end engineering and installation of route-based IP network solutions.
- Performed virtual machine provisioning, VM priority setup and template cloning.
- Escalated emergency technical issues beyond scope to maintain optimum up-time.

2011-03 - 2016-12 System Network Administrator

Hidden Treasure Computers Ltd, Lagos, LA

- Oversaw IT activities to maintain operations by maintaining laptops, tablets and PDAs for over 50 clients.
- Performed and adhered to change management requirements.
- Designed and evaluated WAN and LAN connectivity technologies.
- Diagnosed and executed resolution for all network and server issues.
- Planned and implemented timely upgrades to system hardware and software, resulting in efficiency of computer system and staff.
- Implemented, developed and tested installation and update of file servers, print servers and application servers in all departments.
- Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions.
- Improved operations through consistent hard work and dedication.
- Optimized system security and performance with proactive changes such as timely update of security patches and system update.

2009-08 - 2010-12 **Hardware Engineering Intern**

Guaranty Trust Bank, VI, LA

- Consulted with network engineering staff to evaluate hardware and software requirements for new system development.
- Participated in internal audits of quality management system.
- Traveled to other branch sites to provide prompt resolutions to issues.
- Designed computer hardware components and peripheral devices including power supplies, heat sinks, hard-drives and integrated circuit boards.
- Conducted training sessions for partners, stakeholders and support teams to educate personnel on operational requirements.
- Investigated hardware product issues involving materials and software and devised solutions.
- Researched complex technical issues and provided resolutions when possible.

2009-01 - 2009-02 Hardware Technician

Ajayi Crowther University, Oyo, OY

- Strategically implemented new computer projects and hardware installations to improve workflow for 50 employees.
- Maintained detailed documentation through all phases of development, testing and analysis to enhance organizational productivity.

- Outlined design requirements, BOMs, functional specifications and reports to document development processes.
- Maintained technology equipment performance by configuring, diagnosing and repairing hardware.
- Followed up with clients to verify optimal customer satisfaction following support engagement and problem resolution.
- Installed, modified and repaired software and hardware to resolve technical issues.
- Trained and supported end-users with software, hardware and network standards and use processes.
- Developed and maintained strong client relationships to deliver exceptional customer service and problem resolution.
- Coordinated with IT teams to resolve advanced computer software and hardware problems.

Education

2006-06 - 2009-06	Bachelor of Science: Computer Science Olabisi Onabanjo University O.O.U - Ago-Iwoye Ogun State
2004-06 - 2005-06	Diploma: Data Processing Olabisi Onabanjo University O.O.U - Ago-Iwoye Ogun State
2000-06 - 2004-06	Senior Secondary Certificate: SSCE School of Science - Oyo
2000-11 - 2000-12	West Africa Senior School Certificate: WAEC West Africa Senior School Certificate - Oyo
1998-06 - 2000-06	Junior Secondary Certificate: JSSCE Anglican Methodist Secondary School - Oyo

Accomplishments

- Supervised team of 15 staff members in TStv Africa.
- Achieved smooth streaming of channels by introducing RTMP/HLS for media streaming tasks.
- Used Microsoft Excel to develop inventory tracking spreadsheets.
- Achieved efficient and cost effective virtualization through Proxmox deployment.
- Achieved rapid deployment of computers to staff by introducing common desktop policy and mirroring of system image.
- Achieved fast deployment of virtual servers through container and cloning.
- Resolved data recovery issues through periodic backup of servers and vm.

- Achieved effective system update, common desktop policy and staff login detail through active directory (AD) / domain controller (DC)
- Achieved efficient network security through firewall policy and rules.

Languages



Certifications

2021-04	NSE 1 Network Security Associate - FORTINET NSE Institute - gomw8CPOFa
2021-03	Certified Secure Computer User V2 - EC-Council - ECC2150489637
2021-02	Foundational course in Data Protection and Data Privacy - NG-UNIQUE RESOURCE SOLUTIONS - NURS/DPO/08/006
2020-11	ICSI CyberSecurity Essentials - https://icsiglobal.com - hjshofmwql
2020-10	Certified Computer Networking, Digital Network Security - Alison - 1447-18454226
2020-11	Introduction to Server Administration Services - Alison - 1754-18454226
2020-12	Introduction to Windows Server Administration - Alison - 1753-18454226
2020-12	Microsoft Teams - Alison - 2478-18454226
2020-10	AWS Cloud Fundamentals for System Administrators - udemy - AWS_Cloud_UC-41472ff0-3299-42a4-84c8-295dd0776a79
2020-10	Python And Django Framework For Beginners - udemy - python_UC-32611b0b-b588-49e6-9ae6-89fb66478c1e
2020-10	Introduction to Internet of Things and Cloud - udemy
2020-10	Participate safely and responsibly online - Digital Nigeria - Certificate_60035_53_or3so
2020-10	Software Development Fundamentals - Digital Nigeria - Certificate_60035_66_s82ol
2020-10	Networking fundamentals - Digital Nigeria - Network_Essential_Certificate_60035_64_j98w5

2020-10 Windows operating system fundamentals - Digital Nigeria - Windows_Os_Certificate_60035_63_244dv

2020-10 Security - Digital Nigeria - Security_Certificate_60035_65_07500

Interests

Music

Reading

Travelling